# Art Outline
Title: Unsupervised Clustering of a Large Artwork Dataset and a Visualization by Price
—-
## Introduction
* Why is the art world important
	+ Why is there a societal problem for art - transparency
* What is currently the “technical” problem
	+ We don’t know why artwork is expensive
* What does this study attempt to accomplish
	+ Clusters artwork by similarities
	+ This is something that humans can do, but it’s on a scale that humans can’t handle (80,000 pieces of art)
	+ Recommender systems. Do you want a Monet, but don’t want to spend $100,000
	+ Good for art discovery
	+ We’re used to, others bought similar things recommendations.
	+ A lot of artwork is unlabeled, or poorly labeled.
* What are the impacts of this study
	+ Able to cluster artwork into categories based on intrinsic features
	+ Able to relate those cluster to price data. Are there relationships?

## Background and Previous Research
* Techniques for visual features
	+ Learned or extracted
	+ SALEH 2015
	+ GIST
	+ HOG
	+ Spatial Chromatic Histogram
	+ Pallete Comparison
	+ Standard features

## Image Analysis
* My features:
	+ simple
		- See WHANG et al

## Dimension Reduction — Metric Learning
	+ PCA

## Unsupervised Clustering Algorithms
* Self organizing maps
* Agglomerative clustering
* Multidimensional scaling

## Clustering Results

## Relationship to price data

## Conclusions

